

Alfredo Lino Mendoza

Computer Systems Engineer

☑ alfredolinomendoza@gmail.com 🤰 +52 833 3536046

Profile

I am a Front end developer with 3 years of professional experience. Using React.js, Javascript, Typescript, CSS3, HTML5, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Express.js, Golang, and Svelte. All along an Agile methodology. Also, I am proactive, always trying to learn and improve, communicative, passionate about what I do, and assertive.

Experience

Front end Consultant

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

Apex Systems, Guadalajara, Jalisco

Involved in the successful integration of payment methods at an Ecommerce project. I worked as a front-end consultant. Developed a variety of chores using React.js, Typescript, HTML, CSS, and PHP. All along an Scrum methodology.

Activities:

- React.js development.
- Troubleshooting and debugging code.
- Writing clean, high-quality, high-performance, and maintainable Typescript code
- · Refactoring.
- HTML and CSS.
- Unit testing with JEST, Enzyme and Testing Library.
- Version control with Git and Github.
- Integration of payment methods.
- Development of React.js functional components with Typescript.
- Implementing RESTful APIs and integrating with backend systems.
- Participate in Scrum methodology ceremonies.
- JIRA.

Full stack Software Engineer

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022

IBM, Guadalajara, Jalisco

I developed features for a quote-to-cash web app in a highly competitive team. I worked as a front-end developer for this project using React.js, React hooks, Styled components, Golang, Jest, and Testing Library. All with an Agile methodology.

Activities:

- React.js development.
- Making up React.js functional components out of wireframes.
- Writing clean, high-quality, high-performance, and maintainable Javascript code

Personal Information

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alfredolino

Skills

Svelte.js

Typescript

TailwindCSS

React.js

React Hooks

Javascript (ECMA script 6+)

CSS3

HTML5

Express.js

MongoDB

Java

Golang

Jest

Testing library

AWS

GCP

PHP

Languages

Spanish

English

- Manage state for React.js components.
- Redux, React-Router and Styled-Components.
- Creating endpoints for a Golang grpc backend.
- Implementing RESTful APIs and GRPC backend endpoints.
- HTML and CSS.
- Unit testing with Jest, Enzyme and Testing Library.
- Scrum methodology.
- Version control with Git and Github.
- Estimate requirements with multiple acceptance criteria.
- Participate in Agile methodology ceremonies.
- JIRA.

Front end Developer

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

Zeti.ia, Tampico, Tamaulipas

Starting projects from scratch and developing the design and interactivity of the UI of an AI website. I worked with Svelte and Typescript. Tailwind CSS, Docker, AWS EC2, and GCP Cloud functions. Making components and styling for a web app.

Activities:

- Coding Svelte components with Typescript.
- Translating mock-ups and designs to HTML, CSS and Svelte with high-quality code.
- UI styling with CSS and Tailwind CSS.
- Coding endpoints for Express.js, and Node.js.
- RESTful API development.

Internal project manager

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

ITCM, Ciudad Madero, Tamaulipas

I made a custom web app project for my university to manage and track internal projects. Using React.js, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Jest, and Testing library.

Formation

Computer Systems engineer

Jul 2017 - Dec 2021

Instituto Tecnologico de Ciudad Madero, Ciudad Madero, Tamaulipas